<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title></title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com"/>
	<updated>2019-12-22T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
	<id>https://davidjohnmead.com</id>
	<author>
		<name></name>
		<email></email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hello World</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-03-hello-world/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-02T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-03-hello-world/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Call it a very hard reset, but I wanted to build something new. From the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All previous content has now been deleted from this server. I really don&#39;t know if I&#39;ll add it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s under the hood?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get out of my technology comfort zone. Use something I&#39;m not familiar with. That&#39;s why I ended up using an SSG, or Static Site Generator in longhand. It builds everything locally, using Javascript (shudder), and you just FTP the flat files up to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Sometimes, the old ways are the best.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ctmiller.net/&quot; title=&quot;Chris Miller&#39;s website&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; for hearing me out when I wondered how hard is it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; to build a CMS from scratch. And thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bridgestew.com/&quot; title=&quot;Bridget&#39;s blog&quot;&gt;Bridget&lt;/a&gt; for guiding me through some potholes as she&#39;d built her site using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.io/&quot; title=&quot;official site&quot;&gt;Eleventy&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sure there&#39;s a lot that may &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; work initially. I&#39;m also sure there&#39;s a lot better ways of doing some of the workflow and code. But it&#39;s in a state where I feel &amp;quot;confident&amp;quot; putting it up. Let&#39;s see what breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 years using Twitter, around 7 on Instagram, and I think I&#39;m pretty much done with it at the moment. I haven&#39;t logged in or posted to either in 4 months, so I could leave them inactive, but closing them is starting to feel like the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve already disconnected the apps &amp;amp; services to them. Also requested exports of my data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may just just use &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidmead&quot; title=&quot;main twitter account&quot;&gt;@davidmead&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidjohnmead&quot; title=&quot;alternate twitter account&quot;&gt;@davidjohnmead&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter as an alternative RSS feed - Just post links to the latest posts here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Indieweb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still a fan, and proponent, of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot; title=&quot;own your content&quot;&gt;Indieweb&lt;/a&gt;. Just not sure how much of it I&#39;ll be adding/using here. See my previous statement about social media. I&#39;ve added some of the basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://microformats.org/&quot;&gt;microformats&lt;/a&gt; to my HTML templates, but that may be as far as it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll do a write up of getting started with Eleventy soon. Maybe try for a post a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK. I&#39;m pushing this live. Hopefully the RSS feed is working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Handling broken links</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-04-handling-broken-links/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-03T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-04-handling-broken-links/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Deleting all of my existing content, and there was a lot, means I&#39;ve left a lot of broken links in my wake. With something like Wordpress or Known this is handled for you as a 404 error, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec10.html&quot; title=&quot;W3C information page&quot;&gt;server error code for missing files&lt;/a&gt;, will bring up a pre-built 404 page. Not so when rolling your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.io/docs/quicktips/not-found/&quot; title=&quot;404 page for Eleventy&quot;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; with steps to create one on the Eleventy site. Not too hard to implement, just means a little editing of my .htaccess file, and creating a new page to upload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should now be working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I included an explanation of why the content someone was looking for may not be there, along with a link to the Wayback Machine which has snapshots of billions of web pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 2nd 2019 I deleted all my content, and started fresh. If you&#39;re following a link from elsewhere you can try the Wayback Machine which may have a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also visit the home page to read anything new I&#39;ve posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that should be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Green across the board</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-05-lighthouse-scores/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-05-lighthouse-scores/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was one of the things I had my fingers crossed for when deciding to use a Static Site Generator for my site. As I&#39;m writing my own HTML and CSS from scratch I try and weave in all the best practices I&#39;ve learned over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigating to the homepage in the Chrome browser (incognito mode to make sure no extensions are effecting the results) I opened the Developer tools and clicked audit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/lighthouse-results-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lighthouse audit results all green for new homepage&quot; title=&quot;Audit results all green&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homepage returned the following results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;98% Performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% Accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% Best Practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% SEO (Search Engine Optimization)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not too shabby for a first run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &#39;post&#39; pages faired pretty well too. Only difference was a 97% score for performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/lighthouse-results-post.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lighthouse audit results all green for post pages&quot; title=&quot;Audit results all green&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I know that you can get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.matuzo.at/blog/building-the-most-inaccessible-site-possible-with-a-perfect-lighthouse-score/&quot; title=&quot;Manuel Matuzovic&#39;s post pointing out the dangers of automated testing&quot;&gt;Lighthouse to give a 100% for accessibility on a completely inaccessible site&lt;/a&gt;, but 100% is a great starting point to make changes from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ding on performance, on both mobile and desktop tests, is from using Google Fonts. You&#39;ll get that regardless, and I personally think just using two is fairly restrained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to be sure I had ran the templates through an HTML validator, and the only thing that it reported was &lt;code&gt;rel=&amp;quot;microsub&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. I&#39;m sure as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/micropub/#endpoint-discovery&quot; title=&quot;End point discovery in the spec&quot;&gt;microsub is a W3C spec&lt;/a&gt; this will be corrected soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be keeping an eye on all of this, but not slavishly.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Ambient music from an American painter</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-06-listen-empty-city/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-05T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-06-listen-empty-city/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t remember when I first heard &lt;a href=&quot;http://torlundvall.com/&quot; title=&quot;official site&quot;&gt;Tor Lundvall&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s work, but I&#39;ve now got 3 of his albums I tend to play back-to-back. Out of the 3, &lt;a href=&quot;https://torlundvall.bandcamp.com/album/empty-city&quot; title=&quot;Buy it on Bandcamp&quot;&gt;Empty City&lt;/a&gt; is my favourite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the night trips, I&#39;d stare out the window at abandoned factories, empty warehouses and other structures bathed in the dull orange or greenish glow of streetlights. I wanted to crawl into that hidden world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- Tor Lundvall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the kind of ambient music that mixes big spaces with intimate voices to create a definite mood. And it&#39;s equally great played in any season. It changes slightly if listening in Winter or Summer, but fits both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of his later albums have a mix of instrumental and lyrical tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely worth checking out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Tis The Season</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-06-tis-the-season/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-05T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-06-tis-the-season/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-06-xmas-decoration.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lit Xmas decoration throwing light pattern on wall&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>All trimmed up</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-07-all-trimmed-up/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-06T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-07-all-trimmed-up/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-07-xmas-tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Xmas tree, decorated and lit.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We get a live tree every year. Normally we all pick it out, but this year I dropped the ball. Ended going by myself.</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Code cleanup and the emergency room</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-08-code-and-er/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-07T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-08-code-and-er/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had an idea of the look and layout I wanted for this blog, but I didn&#39;t do a mock in Sketch or anything. I wanted to &amp;quot;find&amp;quot; it while I was marking up the templates. It came together pretty quick. I changed the fonts a couple of times but that was about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after I launched it I saw there was quite a bit I could clean up. Yeah it validated and was semantic, but there was a few things I could do better with CSS Grid..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back through my notes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://rachelandrew.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;official site&quot;&gt;Rachel Andrews&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s workshop at &lt;a href=&quot;https://rustbeltrefresh.com/&quot; title=&quot;Web conference in Cleveland&quot;&gt;Rustbelt Refresh&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a couple of videos from &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/FEnRpy9Xfes&quot; title=&quot;Layout Land video on YouTube&quot;&gt;Jen Simmons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/KOvGeFUHAC0&quot; title=&quot;Mozilla Dev video on YouTube&quot;&gt;Miriam Suzanne&lt;/a&gt;, I quickly dumped a lot of classes and employed grid in 3 of the Eleventy templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Base template&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main HTML template now uses grid for its structure. The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;main&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;footer&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; are set as rows. With the footer always being at the bottom of the page with just four lines of CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;display:grid;
grid-gap: 1em;
grid-template-rows: auto 1fr auto;
min-height: 100vh;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content templates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a couple of different templates at the moment, for different types of content. One for mini album reviews, one for photos, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these few lines of CSS I can get 2 columns laid out for the &#39;listen&#39; type, within the grid that wraps the whole page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;display: grid;
grid-template-columns: 240px 1fr;
grid-gap: 1.5em;
grid-auto-rows: minmax(auto, auto);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Emergency room&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-08-jjm-er.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Josh in a triage room&quot; title=&quot;Josh in a triage room&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halfway through writing this Josh came home with Julie. He had been complaining about a pain in his back in the morning. It hadn&#39;t got better with an Advil. Seeing as the local Urgent Care isn&#39;t open on Sunday, it was a trip to the ER as he was in pain walking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain pills, muscle relaxant injection, and an icy-hot patch later, he feels a little better and has a note to excuse hime from gym this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that&#39;s all the excitement for the week out the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Art or Decoration?</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-10-art-or-decoration/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-09T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-10-art-or-decoration/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-10-xmas-art.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging pieces make up shape of xmas tree&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
We have a &#39;Main Street&#39; at my work. The centre place on our ground floor. This year it contains this great piece.
&lt;p&gt;We have art all around the HQ (not surprising with one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cleveland.com/arts/2019/12/dealer-tire-ceo-scott-mueller-leads-by-example-as-new-chairman-of-cleveland-museum-of-art.html&quot; title=&quot;newspaper article&quot;&gt;our owners&lt;/a&gt; is Chairman of Cleveland Museum of Art) and having something like this beats the normal corporate Xmas trees you see at a lot of places.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Problem with Eleventy, RSS, and images</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-11-problem-with-rss-and-images/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-10T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-11-problem-with-rss-and-images/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed that in the RSS feed of this site, images within posts only show up some of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the generated source code, they are all within the main block of the content being displayed in the item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick duck-duck-go-ing and I came across a couple of general RSS issues along the same lines. Some was where the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; was being ignored as it wasn&#39;t in a containing element. Easy fix I thought. I made sure all the images were in a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, as the ones showing up in the feed were part of the written post (in the middle of content) as opposed to a specific &amp;quot;photo post&amp;quot; which was just the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element on its own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&#39;t make any difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here comes CDATA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I noticed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.indieweb.org/dev/2019-12-11/1576080408129100&quot;&gt;conversation on the indieweb chat&lt;/a&gt; about images and RSS. Wrapping things between &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;![CDATA[&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;]]&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; was a recommendation. I checked at &lt;a href=&quot;https://granary.io/&quot; title=&quot;The social web translator&quot;&gt;Granary.io&lt;/a&gt;. After plugging a URL of one of my posts in that, the output did have those CDATA tags around it. So I added those into my &lt;code&gt;feed.njk&lt;/code&gt; file. No luck. In fact it made the HTML be written out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then re-read through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/plugins/rss/&quot;&gt;Eleventy post about adding RSS&lt;/a&gt; a couple of times. Everything in my code matched, but something nagged at me about the &lt;code&gt;htmlToAbsoluteUrls&lt;/code&gt; part. What if the URL for the image wasn&#39;t there when the page is being built?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo post template&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created a specific template for photo posts. I use this in the front matter...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;layout: layouts/layout-photo
imgSRC: /img/
imgALT:
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...to pull in the photo so I can style it. So if it&#39;s not in the actual content until the flat HTML is &amp;quot;built&amp;quot; the feed file won&#39;t pull it in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this is an issue with all static site generators.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>NOM - Spicy Chao Shou</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-11-spicy-chao-shou/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-10T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-11-spicy-chao-shou/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-11-spicy-chao-shou.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pork stuffed wontons in spicy chili oil&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only did I have the normal serving of soup dumplings, but today&#39;s sharp cold weather called for something a little hotter. Love those spicy chao shou from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yelp.com/biz/lj-shanghai-cleveland&quot; title=&quot;official Yelp page&quot;&gt;LJ Shanghai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hypertext in my Markdown</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-12-hypertext-in-my-markdown/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-11T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-12-hypertext-in-my-markdown/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-11-problem-with-rss-and-images/&quot; title=&quot;Problem with Eleventy, RSS, and images&quot;&gt;previous post about this&lt;/a&gt; I thought I&#39;d solved it, but no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well now I really think I have, but it meant a slight template change as well as adding some HTML into my Markdown files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;code&gt;layout-photo.njk&lt;/code&gt; file I had the following block&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;e-content&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
	&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img class=&amp;quot;u-photo img-polaroid&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;&#39;{&#39;{ imgSRC }&#39;}&#39;&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&#39;{&#39;{ imgALT }&#39;}&#39;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
	&#39;{&#39;{ content | safe }&#39;}&#39;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would then pull the &lt;code&gt;imgSRC&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;imgALT&lt;/code&gt; that I had in the &lt;code&gt;post.md&lt;/code&gt; frontmatter when built.  I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; this is what was causing the images not to show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commenting out the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element in the template and moving that into the post actually seemed to cause the images to show up in my feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure if pasting the HTML wholesale into the Markdown file is &amp;quot;right&amp;quot;, but it seems to work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Crow Tree</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-14-crow-tree/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-13T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-14-crow-tree/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-14-crow-tree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black and white photo of crows in the Winter trees&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Lunch with Josh</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-14-lunch-with-josh/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-13T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-14-lunch-with-josh/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After getting Josh&#39;s haircut, a new style of his choosing, we headed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sugarbowlwilloughby.com/&quot; title=&quot;Pho and bakery&quot;&gt;Sugar Bowl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We both had a bowl Pho Tai. A big serving of Vietnamese noodle soup with rare steak topped with cilantro, scallion and onions. Delicious on a cold rainy day like today. Also shared an appetizer of &#39;Country Wings&#39; (crispy fried with a sweet chili sauce to dip).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-14-pho.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of bowl containing Pho&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>People are starting to want to own content again?</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-14-people-want-own-the-content/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-13T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-14-people-want-own-the-content/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a fair amount of chatter recently about hosting your own content again. This is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan Curtis tweeted out about how Medium is now changing their policy, and how it effects him...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;So, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Medium?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@medium&lt;/a&gt; has done it? Only one free article per user even for authors that don&amp;#39;t want a paywall? Glad &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eightshapes?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@eightshapes&lt;/a&gt; has setup and partially migrated to our .com too. I know what I&amp;#39;m getting done by 1/1/2020. 😠 Too sad.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nathan Curtis (@nathanacurtis) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nathanacurtis/status/1204889629276676096?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura Kalbag wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://24ways.org/2019/its-time-to-get-personal/&quot; title=&quot;article on 24 ways&quot;&gt;It’s Time to Get Personal&lt;/a&gt; where she looks at the wasteland of personal websites, that could start to become a lush community garden of shared thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially it means when we are not paying for mainstream tech with money, we are paying for it with our privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Jack Dorsey tweeted out that they are funding a team to develop something &amp;quot;new&amp;quot;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Twitter is funding a small independent team of up to five open source architects, engineers, and designers to develop an open and decentralized standard for social media. The goal is for Twitter to ultimately be a client of this standard. 🧵&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; jack 🌍🌏🌎 (@jack) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jack/status/1204766078468911106?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;December 11, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...which of course led to a load of replies pointing out the already abundant ideas already in place on the web including Indieweb, ActivityPub, etc. Naturally blockchain got thrown around a lot too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great read was Anil Dash&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://anildash.com/2019/12/10/link-in-bio-is-how-they-tried-to-kill-the-web/&quot; title=&quot;post on his website&quot;&gt;“Link In Bio” is a slow knife&lt;/a&gt; where he lays out how Instagram (and other silo&#39;s) keep people in the walled garden by limiting the access to external content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe 2020 will see the rise of something federated and syndicated, yet personal.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Declaring podcast bankruptcy</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-16-podcast-bankruptcy/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-15T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-16-podcast-bankruptcy/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As with e-mail I&#39;ve hit the tipping point where I can&#39;t possible listen to all the podcasts I subscribe to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only listen to &amp;quot;conversational&amp;quot; podcasts when I&#39;m either driving or doing nothing. That doesn&#39;t amount to a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Daily time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the day I&#39;m either in meetings, or trying to get back into that &#39;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)&quot;&gt;flow state&lt;/a&gt;&#39;. Neither of which let me drop in-and-out of narrative or conversation audio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do have some music podcasts which I&#39;ll keep for that time. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sheeldz.co.uk/radio/blog/&quot;&gt;Monday Graveyard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ultimathule.info/&quot;&gt;Ultima Thule&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theblackdogma.com/&quot;&gt;The Black Dog&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://echoes.org/&quot;&gt;Echoes&lt;/a&gt; are a few.  These range from ambient to electronic dance with a little conversation between mixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ones I&#39;m having to let go are the long form conversations.  Now that, I guess, podcasts are &amp;quot;a thing&amp;quot; the length and advertising have increased. They aren&#39;t bad, and I&#39;ll miss them, but that&#39;s the problem right now-I&#39;m missing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An ungodly amount&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently have 58 episodes sitting in my queue. Most around 40-60 minutes in length. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pca.st/h5ovwmhi&quot;&gt;John Gruber&#39;s 2hr 45m episode&lt;/a&gt; will go unheard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they keeping piling in. Some have even ended and I haven&#39;t got around to hearing them all.  So I&#39;m saying goodbye to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-16-podcast-bankruptcy/daringfireball.net/thetalkshow&quot;&gt;The Talk Show With John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://offcamera.com/&quot;&gt;Off Camera with Sam Jones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evergreenpodcasts.com/design-everywhere&quot;&gt;Design Everywhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tanispodcast.com/&quot;&gt;Tanis&lt;/a&gt; (great, but I don&#39;t know when it&#39;ll be back)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicradioalliance.com/the-last-movie&quot;&gt;The Last movie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rabbitspodcast.com/&quot;&gt;Rabbits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trailersfromhell.com/podcast&quot;&gt;The Movies That Made Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://longnow.org/&quot;&gt;Long Now: Seminars About Long-term Thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eureka.baronfig.com/&quot;&gt;Eureka by Baron Fig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/programs/invisibilia&quot;&gt;Invisibilia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://audioboom.com/channel/soundtrackingwithedithbowman&quot;&gt;Soundtracking with Edith Bowman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ctrlclickcast.com/&quot;&gt;CTRL+Click Cast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I list them here in the hope I can pick them back up again. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now my list is down, and with the Xmas holidays coming up, I may actually catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Departmental cooking</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-19-departmental-cooking/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-19-departmental-cooking/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As with most companies, I imagine, we&#39;d went for our departmental Xmas lunch. But this was a bit different for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out in Chesterland is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lpscinc.com/&quot; title=&quot;Ohio&#39;s premier professional and recreational culinary institute for all levels&quot;&gt;The Loretta Paganini School of Cooking&lt;/a&gt;. Today we were to cook a 3-course meal of Caprese Salad with Balsamic Drizzle, Homemade Pasta with vegetables topped with Chicken Scallopine in Lemon Caper Sauce, and ending with a Peach Cobbler &amp;amp; ice-cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-19-cooking-teams.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;teams cooking in professional kitchen&quot; title=&quot;teams cooking in professional kitchen&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being introduced to our instructors we split into groups. Each handling a certain part of the meal. I was in &#39;Team Chicken&#39;. 3 of us trimmed, cut, and smashed chicken into thin pieces. Then dredged them in seasoned flour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other 3 prepped vegetables and roasted them for our vegetarians. We all took turns cooking the chicken in oil &amp;amp; butter, making the lemon and caper sauce, and finally adding the chicken back in the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-19-lunch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the final dish - Chicken Scallopine in Lemon Caper Sauce on a bed of pasta and vegetables&quot; title=&quot;the final dish&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s always interesting seeing what, and how, other people work. I picked up a few tips from our great instructors, as well as getting to have some fun with my co-workers and eat a very delicious meal.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>WFH Breakfast</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-19-wfh-breakfast/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-19-wfh-breakfast/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the odd occasion I do work from home, it&#39;s always a treat to cook breakfast. Bacon, egg, and a fried slice is my go-to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-19-breakfast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bacon, egg, and fried bread with a black coffee&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Thank you breakfast</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-20-breakfast/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-19T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-20-breakfast/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a thank you our bosses cooked us breakfast this morning. Various tamales from Texas including pork, beef, spinach, and black bean. Eggs, blueberry french toast, oats, and (of course) bacon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-20-breakfast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Various tamales, bacon, eggs, and queso&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>BACON</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-22-bacon/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-21T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-22-bacon/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not much beats bacon on a warm baguette for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-22-breakfast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;close up of cooked bacon on a baguette&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A warm Christmas</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-23-a-warm-christmas/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-22T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-23-a-warm-christmas/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Only two days from Xmas and it&#39;s an odd one. In the 50&#39;s and the days don&#39;t seem to be as short as they normally are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;u-photo img-polaroid&quot; src=&quot;https://davidjohnmead.com/img/2019-12-23-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset with dark trees in front&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>