<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title></title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com"/>
	<updated>2019-12-02T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
	<id>https://davidjohnmead.com</id>
	<author>
		<name></name>
		<email></email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hello World</title>
		<link href="https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-03-hello-world/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-02T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://davidjohnmead.com/posts/2019-12-03-hello-world/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Call it a very hard reset, but I wanted to build something new. From the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All previous content has now been deleted from this server. I really don&#39;t know if I&#39;ll add it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s under the hood?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get out of my technology comfort zone. Use something I&#39;m not familiar with. That&#39;s why I ended up using an SSG, or Static Site Generator in longhand. It builds everything locally, using Javascript (shudder), and you just FTP the flat files up to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Sometimes, the old ways are the best.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ctmiller.net/&quot; title=&quot;Chris Miller&#39;s website&quot;&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; for hearing me out when I wondered how hard is it &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; to build a CMS from scratch. And thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bridgestew.com/&quot; title=&quot;Bridget&#39;s blog&quot;&gt;Bridget&lt;/a&gt; for guiding me through some potholes as she&#39;d built her site using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.io/&quot; title=&quot;official site&quot;&gt;Eleventy&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sure there&#39;s a lot that may &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; work initially. I&#39;m also sure there&#39;s a lot better ways of doing some of the workflow and code. But it&#39;s in a state where I feel &amp;quot;confident&amp;quot; putting it up. Let&#39;s see what breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 years using Twitter, around 7 on Instagram, and I think I&#39;m pretty much done with it at the moment. I haven&#39;t logged in or posted to either in 4 months, so I could leave them inactive, but closing them is starting to feel like the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve already disconnected the apps &amp;amp; services to them. Also requested exports of my data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may just just use &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidmead&quot; title=&quot;main twitter account&quot;&gt;@davidmead&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/davidjohnmead&quot; title=&quot;alternate twitter account&quot;&gt;@davidjohnmead&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter as an alternative RSS feed - Just post links to the latest posts here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Indieweb&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still a fan, and proponent, of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot; title=&quot;own your content&quot;&gt;Indieweb&lt;/a&gt;. Just not sure how much of it I&#39;ll be adding/using here. See my previous statement about social media. I&#39;ve added some of the basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://microformats.org/&quot;&gt;microformats&lt;/a&gt; to my HTML templates, but that may be as far as it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll do a write up of getting started with Eleventy soon. Maybe try for a post a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK. I&#39;m pushing this live. Hopefully the RSS feed is working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>